《法外情真》前情回顾
Previously on The Guardian.
蒂芙尼·斯科维奇
Tiffany·Skovich.
这就是他三年前拉皮条那女孩儿
That's the girl he was pimping three years ago.
没人在乎这些女孩
These girls... nobody cares.
她们得到的都是不好的交易
All they ever got is rotten deals.
简之家是个救济站
Jean's place is a shelter,
专为你这样的女孩准备的
for young girls like you.
那是说  我能去那儿
So I can go there,
就不用去少管所了吗
and not the juvie.
我一直在考虑律所的事儿
I've been thinking about the firm...
我觉得是时候  让你被提携至合作伙伴了
I think it's time for you to be named as managing partner.
我们现在就该采取行动了
We should act now.
这是维多利亚
This is Victoria...
艾滋支持会的主席
Chairman for AAids alliance.
我  我喜欢你
I.. like you.
很复杂
It's complicated...
我被要求辞去我在这里的职务了
I've been asked to resign my position here.
- 立即生效  - 他们给了我  你的职位
- effective immediately. - I've been offered your job.
我接受了
I took it.
阿尔文
Alvin..
你想留下吗
Do you wanna stay?
做你的员工吗
On your staff?
阿尔文  这里需要你
Alvin, this place needs you.
周末公司的团建巴士
The vans for this weekend's firm retreat
将从弗里克大厦对面的停车场出发
will be leaving from the parking lot across from the Frick Building
明天早上六点半准时
at exactly 6:30 tomorrow morning.
我们的会议室会提供咖啡和饮料
Coffee and Danishes will be provided in our conference room
从六点到六点十五分
between 6:00 and 6:15,
并且业务绩效部的同事
and the people at Business Performance
已经制定了完整的活动计划
have put together a full schedule of activities
从建立信任的练习
ranging from trust building exercises
到排球  再到演讲论坛
to volleyball to speaker forums.
呃  当然车间出席也是必须的
Uh, workshop attendance is, of course, mandatory.
嗨
Hello.
早啊
Morning.
早  希拉
Morning, Sheila.
你是最棒的
You're the best.
- 哦  阿尔文  - 露露
- Oh, Alvin. - Lulu.
露露大美女
Beautiful Lulu.
- 什么  - 你真是光芒四射
- What? - You're radiant.
哦  得了吧
Oh, please.
我在三个月里胖了23磅
I've gained 23 pounds in the last three months.
- 太好了  - 来我办公室坐坐吧
- Fantastic. - You want to come in my office?
当然
Sure.
怎么了
What is it?
呃  我刚刚跟卢茨法官打完电话
Well, I just got off the phone with Judge Lutz.
好吧
Right.
那么  你跟他说  塞到他的屁股里  是什么意思
So... what is this about you telling him to ''shove it up his ass''?
- 他给你打电话了吗  - 好吧  是的  我得管这个地方  阿尔文
- He called you? - Well, yeah, I do run the place, Alvin.
- 娘娘腔  - 什么
- Sissy. - What?
哦  我已经认识伯纳德·卢茨二十年了  他居然打我小报告
Oh, I've known Bernard·Lutz for 20 years, and he's telling on me?
这并不是重点好吧
Well, that's not really the point.
我都知道了  露露  我知道了
I know the point, Lulu. It's taken.
- 阿尔文  通常来说  - 怎么了
- Alvin, in general-- - Yes?
通常来说你已经错过很多工作了
ln general, you have been missing a lot of work.
- 是这样  - 是的
- Right. - Right.
那么  有什么我能做的来帮助你提高工作效率吗
So is there maybe something I could do to help you be more productive?
-帮助我吗  - 对
- Help me? - Right.
帮我更高效吗
Help me be more productive.
对  阿尔文  你要明白  我只是在试着
Yeah, Alvin. You know, I'm just trying--
如果我说  是的  我需要你的帮助  那你打算怎么做呢
Let's say I said yes that I need help. What are you going to do?
看到没有  你帮不了我
You see? You can't help me.
我艺高没人帮得了  明白吗
I'm beyond being helped. Okay?
那好吧
Okay, then.
我不干了
I quit.
- 阿尔文  - 不干了  我不干了
- Alvin. - No, I quit.
别往心里去  我不干了
No hard feelings, but I quit.
认真讲  你真的挺好看的
And you do look great. I'm serious about that.
第三季  第十八集
法外真情
翻译   大淘   子
校对  油 球
特效  转轮 枪
法林先生
Mr. Fallin.
露露告诉我  说你辞职了
Lulu told me that you-- that you quit.
27年  将近九千个客户
Twenty-seven years and nearly 9,000 clients.
我还能做什么
What more can I do?
好吧  你知道的  阿尔文  如果  如果有什么我能帮你的
Well, you know, Alvin, if there's-- if there's anything that I can do for you--
- 我要结婚了  - 是吗
- I'm getting married. - Huh?
今天早上我跟维多利亚求婚了
I proposed to Victoria this morning.
哇哦
Wow.
那真的是  恭喜
That's-- Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
然后  我一直在想  希望你能做我的伴郎
And I was thinking. I want you to be my Best Man.
我吗  为什么
Me? Why?
还用多说吗  不言自明啊
Res ipsa loquitor. Speaks for itself.
只需要说你答应了就好
Just say you'll do it.
阿尔文  谢谢
Alvin, thank you.
我  真的是受宠若惊
I'm-- I'm flattered.
我只是  我不知道是否  呃
I just-- I don't know if, uh--
而且  我快要死了
And... I'm dying.
- 什么  - 肌萎缩性侧索硬化症  卢伽雷氏症
- What? - ALS. Lou Gehrig's disease.
如果你能不告诉任何人  我会很感激
I'd appreciate it if you didn't tell anybody about it.
你知道卢·格里克得了一百多分
Did you know that Lou·Gehrig drove in more than a hundred runs
在连续的13个赛季中
for 13 consecutive seasons?
13个
13.
我很抱歉  但是我得跟别人说说
I'm sorry. I had to tell somebody.
天哪  阿尔文
God, Alvin.
是啊  我开始被东西绊倒
Yeah. I started tripping over things.
最开始并没有真的注意到
Didn't really notice it at first.
之后  我时不时的说不清楚话
Then once in a while my words would get slurry.
你注意到过吗
Did you ever notice that?
我去看精神科医生了
I been seeing a neurologist.
事实上  看了三个医生
Three neurologists... actually.
今天主治医生终于给我诊断了
The main guy finally diagnosed me today.
但是  别说这个了  我们还是说说我的单身派对吧
But... Iet's not dwell. Instead, let's talk about my bachelor party.
是啊  嗯  是的  我会  我会把东西一起准备好
Yeah, um-- yeah, I'll-- I'll put something together for you.
呃  不用了  已经准备好了
Uh-- no need. Taken care of everything.
给我们两个人定了两张去洛杉矶  加利福尼亚的头等舱机票
Booked us two tickets-- First Class-- to Los Angeles, California.
- 阿尔文  - 早上第一班航班
- Alvin-- - First flight out in the morning.
阿尔文  我得去  我得去参加公司聚会
Alvin, I got to-- I got to do this Fallin & Fallin retreat.
哦  来吧  尼克  加利福尼亚啊  阳光之洲啊
Oh, come on, Nick. California. The Sunshine State.
不夜城  洛杉矶啊
Los Angeles. The City that never sleeps.
早上八点的航班
Flight leaves at 8:OO.
- 在门口等你啊  - 好吧
- Meet you at the gate. - Okay.
你们有人知道霍华德·塔夫脱吗
Did any of you know Howard·Taft?
我这辈子见过的最卑鄙的混蛋
The meanest son of a bitch I ever met in my life.
我跟你说  也是宾夕法尼亚周最贱的百万富翁
And the cheapest millionaire in Pennsylvania, I can tell you that.
嘿  嗯  我能跟你说几句话吗
Hey. Uh, can I talk to you for a second?
哦  我正跟他们说霍华德·塔夫托呢
Oh, I was just telling them about Howard·Taft.
好吧  很抱歉  我需要跟你说几句话  我得去赶航班
Right. I'm sorry, I need to talk to you. I got a plane to catch.
哦  这样啊  好吧
Well, yeah. Okay.
走  去吧  先过去
Go. Go ahead. Go ahead.
- 抱歉打扰一下  - 早啊
- Excuse me a minute. - Morning.
到底怎么了  儿子
What the hell, son?
很抱歉  我去不了了
I'm sorry. I can't go.
你知不知道我们在这件事上花了四万三千美元
Do you realize we're spending $43,000 on this thing?
实在抱歉  但是我得和阿尔文去洛杉矶
I'm sorry, but I have to go to L.A. with Alvin.
- 为什么啊  - 是私事
- Why? - It's personal.
- 什么  - 我不能说
- What? - I can't talk about it.
这跟社区服务有什么关系吗
What, does this have to do with that community service?
不  只是私事
No. It's personal.
儿子  你看  这整个想法的目的是
Son, look, the whole idea here is to--
建立一点公司的士气
is to build a little company morale...
让你在公司的核心位置
with you right in the middle of it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
可以吗  我必须得走
All right? I have to go.
等回来我再跟你解释
And I'll explain when I get back.
等等  等一下
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你现在能离开我们州吗
Are you even allowed to leave the State?
是的
Yeah.
不  我一会就到  别担心
No, I'll be there. Don't worry.
给我打电话啊  我会去的
Just call me. I'll be there.
好吧  那一会再跟你聊  好吗
Okay, I'll talk to you later, right?
好的  拜
Okay. Bye.
你怎么进这间办公室的
How did you get in this office?
我有个预约
I have an appointment.
这个门是开着的
The door was open.
不  不是开着的
No, it wasn't.
我到的时候就是开着的
It was when I got here.
你什么时候到的
When did you get here?
今天早上  阿尔文在哪
This morning. Where's Alvin?
- 你叫什么名字  - 蒂凡尼
- What's your name? - Tiffany.
- 蒂凡尼什么  - 阿尔文在哪
- Tiffany what? - Where's Alvin?
阿尔文不在这工作了
Alvin doesn't work here anymore.
- 阿尔文走了吗  - 是的  他退休了
- Alvin's gone? - Yeah, he's retired.
嘿  等一下
Hey, wait a second.
等等  你要去哪儿
Wait a second. Where're you going?
现在飞往洛杉矶的三号航班
Now boarding flight Three to Los Angeles,
头等舱和星级里程会员请登机
first Class and Star Mileage members.
同时也欢迎商务舱的乘客登机
We'd also like to welcome our Business Class passengers at this time.
呃  你看  阿尔文  我们可能得登机了
Ah, you know, Alvin, we should probably board now.
你知道卢·格里克开过一百多次
Did you know that Lou·Gehrig drove in more than a hundred runs--
是啊  你告诉过我
Yeah, you told me.
连续2130场比赛  一整天
Played in 2, 130 consecutive games, and one day
他只是让自己脱离了阵容
he just takes himself out of the line-up.
- 阿尔文  - 2130场比赛
- Alvin... - 2, 130 consecutive games--
-阿尔文  - 来了
- Alvin. - All right.
我的意思是  想像一下
I mean, imagine that.
- 拿票了吗  - 拿了
- You have your ticket? - Yeah.
- 不好意思  - 这真的太棒了
- Excuse me. - This is great.
我以前从来没飞过头等舱
I've never flown First Class before.
- 麻烦让一下  - 谢谢
- Excuse me. - Thank you.
- 抱歉  - 劳驾
- I'm sorry. - Excuse me.
大家早上好
Good morning, everybody.
早
Morning.
每个人都有一个信封
You all have envelopes.
里面有一个卡片  上面写着一个词或词组
lnside is a card with a word or a phrase.
来吧  打开你们的信封
Go ahead. Open your envelopes.
好的
Okay.
现在  请各位在屋子的四周走动
Now, I want you to walk around the room.
将自己重新介绍给你们的同事  再问问他们  他们的词是什么
Reintroduce yourself to your co-workers and ask them what their word is.
然后找就会找到你的搭档
You'll know when you've found a match.
开始吧
Go ahead.
- 花生酱  - 通心粉
- Peanut butter. - Macaroni.
- 你的是什么  - 葡萄
- What do you have? - Grapes.
通心粉
Macaroni.
- 花生酱  - 不是
- Peanut butter. - No.
- 是通心粉吗  - 果冻
- Macaroni?
- Jelly.
当你找到你的搭档  也就找到了你的周末室友
When you've found your match, you've found your weekend roommate.
- 花生酱  - 最近怎么样
- Peanut butter. - How you doing?
呃  花生酱
Uh, peanut butter.
哦  好吧  果冻
Oh, well, jelly.
很好  好吧
Great. Well, all right.
我们往这边飞的时候你向下看了吗
Did you look down when we were flying in here?
这样的一个地方真的是太赞了
Amazing, the possibilities of a place like this.
闻到茉莉香了吗
Smell that-- jasmine.
真好
Amazing.
还有美女们  哦  我的天啊
And the women... Oh, my God.
真是难以置信
They're unbelievable.
我们打开广播吧
Let's turn on the radio.
哇哦  摇滚  太大声了吗  抱歉
Wow, rock 'n' roll. Too loud? Sorry.
- 谢谢  - 谢谢
- Thank you. - Thanks.
那  去酒店吧  我们早点办理入住
So... go to the hotel, got us an early check-in,
看看游泳池  吃点午餐  然后  谁知道呢
check out the pool, little lunch, and then... who knows?
棒极了
Fantastic.
希望你不介意跟我同住
Hope you don't mind sharing.
他们叫这个总统套房
They call this the Presidential Suite.
据我所知  查克·D和弗拉瓦·弗拉夫在这时就住在这
I understand that Chuck·D and Flava·Flav stay here when they're in town.
你刚刚说弗拉瓦·弗拉夫
Did you say Flava Flav?
是的  你知道的  《国民公敌》里面的嘛
Yeah, you know... Public Enemy.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是给你的
Here you go.
- 非常感谢  - 谢谢
- Thank you very much. - Thank you.
哇哦  阿尔文  这间房间太贵了
Wow, Alvin, this is a very expensive room.
- 我请客  - 这是你的单身派对
- My treat. - It's your bachelor party.
- 我应该我买单的  - 不  不用  我来付
- I should be paying for this. - No. No-no, I'm paying.
- 你认真的吗  - 是的
- Are you sure? - Yes.
嘿  呃  我就是想谢谢你
Hey, uh... I just want to thank you...
能陪我来这
for coming here with me.
呃  会很有意思的
Ah, it'll be fun.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 嘿  -嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
今天早上蒂凡尼·斯科维奇来你的给办公室了
Tiffany·Skovich was in your office this morning?
是的  我觉得是她闯进来的
Right. I think she broke in.
太奇怪了
Strange.
事实上  我觉得她是睡在这里了
Actually, I think she slept here.
好吧  如果她再来这  给我打电话或者直接打给警察
Well, if she comes by again, call me or call the police.
好的  你知道  我看过她的档案
Okay. You know, I read her file.
真是令人惊讶  她是个妓女
It's kind of surprising that she's a prostitute.
她还这么年轻
She's so young.
她还能回到简之家吗
ls she going to be able to go back to Jane's Place?
不行  昨天她被开除了
No. She was expelled yesterday.
在我们转移她之前逃跑了
Ran off before we could transfer her.
呃  所以她是要去哪里呢
Hm... so where is she going to go?
少管所  一旦我们找到她  真是太遗憾了
Juvie... once we find her. It's a shame, really.
对于她这样的女孩来说  简之家是一个再好不过的地方了
Jane's Place is as good as it gets for a girl with her record.
她错过了一个好机会
She blew a great chance.
哦  太冷了
Oh, it's cold.
冻死了  冻死了  冻死了  冻死了 冻死了
Cold-- cold-- cold-- cold. Cold-- cold-- cold-- cold.
哦
Oh...
啊哈  暖和
Aah... hot.
太暖和了
Hot.
- 你不来游泳吗  - 不  我有些工作还需要弄
- You're not going to swim? - No. I've got some work to do.
好吧
Okay.
哈
Aah...
我真真实实的感受到周围的水
I can really feel the water.
很好啊
Good.
你知道我在说什么吗
You know what I'm talking about?
因为某些原因  我在这感觉更好一点
l-- I feel better here, for some reason. Strong.
很好啊
Great.
也许我应该搬来洛杉矶住
Maybe I should just move to Los Angeles.
- 也许吧  - 不
- Maybe. - No.
- 我会想死你们这群家伙的  - 我们也会想你
- I'd miss you guys too much. - Miss you, too.
谢谢
Thank you.
你太放不开了
You don't open up much.
有时候我会想知道  是不是我或者
I just wonder sometimes, is it me or is--
不  是我自己的原因
No, it's just me.
快点  咱们走吧
Come on, let's go.
- 什么  - 兄弟  我们今天有很多事情要做
- What? - We got a lot to do, buddy.
很多事情  快点
A lot to do. Come on.
快点  拦下他
Come on, pick him up.
投篮
Shoot.
一整天  嘿  一整天
All day long, baby! All day long.
这就是我一直在说的
That's what I'm talking about.
你来防他  尼克
He's yours, Nick.
拦下他
Get him.
- 拦下他  - 哦
- Get him. - Oh!
游戏而已
Game.
- 下一个是谁 - 尼克
- Who's next? - Nick.
怎么了
What happened?
- 你应该拦住他的  - 你看到了吗
- You're supposed to block that. - Did you see that?
- 别担心了  - 我没有
- Don't worry about it. - I'm not.
我不知道你不会打
I didn't know you couldn't play.
呃  我只是
Uh, I just--
团队运动  阿尔文  并不是  你是到  并不适合我
Team sports, Alvin, not really, you know, my thing.
威尼斯海滩
Venice Beach.
这个地方很有传奇色彩
This place is legendary.
所有的球员都在这玩
All the ballers played here.
不管怎么样都是很严肃的事
The serious ones anyway.
马库斯·约翰逊  拜伦·斯科特  克里斯·米尔斯
Marcus·Johnson, Byron·Scott, Chris·Mills,
- 菲利普  辣酱  冠军  - 你知道的  阿尔文  是很有意思
- Philip ''Hot Sauce'' Champion. - You know, Alvin, that was fun
但是我需要回酒店  然后有几个电话要打
but I've got to get back to the hotel and make some calls.
不行  咱们去游泳吧
No. Let's go swimming.
穿什么
ln what?
快来吧  尼克  你在害怕什么
Come on, Nick. What're you afraid of?
- 你穿着你的内裤呢  - 然后呢
- You're in your underwear. - So?
那小不点也这样穿的
So's that guy.
快点  你来吗
Come on. You comin' in?
你去吧
You go.
啊
Aah!
哦  我的天哪
Oh, my God!
哦  呃  你想留浴室的灯吗
Oh. Uh., do you want the bathroom light on?
不  我不用  怎么了  你需要吗
No, I don't. Why? You?
哦  有时候当我在一个陌生的地方
Oh, sometimes when I'm in a new place...
哦  好吧  当然  你想开着  那就开着吧
Oh, yeah, sure. You want it on, leave it on.
好的 那太好了
Okay. Great.
- 伯顿  - 怎么了
- Burton? - Yeah?
尼克怎么了
What happened with Nick?
哦  他得去
Oh, he had to...
去洛杉矶
go to Los Angeles.
- 洛杉矶吗  - 是的
- Los Angeles? - Yeah.
为什么啊
Why?
有些私事
Some personal matter.
- 他还好吗  - 是的  他很好
- Is he okay? - Yeah. He's fine.
那就好  我们很惦记他
Well, good. A few of us were concerned.
嗯  今天过得真开心啊
Hmm. What a fantastic day.
我想说  那是
I mean, that was...
嘿  那是一个明星坐在你后面呢吗
Hey, is that someone famous sitting behind you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得是个明星
I think that's someone famous.
呃  有可能是吧
Well, maybe it is.
- 凯撒做的真不错  - 嗯
- This is a very good Caesar. - Hmm.
那你什么时候结婚呢
So when're you getting married?
还没定日子  我就是昨天问了她一下  所以
Haven't set a date yet. I just asked her yesterday, so...
你还没有告诉她吗
You didn't tell her yet?
是的
Right.
其实  我去她的办公室想要告诉她  但是之后
Well, I went to her office to tell her but then...
我明白了
the clarity--
这个消息让我明白一点  我只想和她在一起
The news gave, me this clarity and I just had to ask her to stay with me.
而且使我坚定了这个想法
And... it was powerful.
- 需要收拾走吗  - 哦  谢谢
- May I? - Oh, thank you.
谢谢  味道非常好
Thank you. That was dee-licious.
- 你相信治疗师吗  - 你想说什么样的
- Do you believe in healers? - Like what? What do you mean?
好吧  有的人有治疗的力量
Well, people who have healing powers,
他们可以  呃  通过意念或者能量做一些事情
who can, uh, do things with energy or thought.
我不知道
I don't know.
据说有人就有这样的天赋
Supposedly there are people who have gifts like that.
我读了一些令人难以置信的故事  我猜有的时候真的有效
I've been reading incredible stories and sometimes it works, I guess.
好吧
Great.
- 什么  你不相信吗  - 我
- What? You don't think it can? - l.. .
你知道我怎么想的吗  尼克
You know what I think, Nick?
我觉得埃里克·埃斯特拉达就坐在那
I think that's Erik·Estrada sitting over there.
嘿  埃里克
Hey, Erik!
你好啊
What's up?
蒂凡尼  在那等着
Tiffany, wait right there.
给你
Here you go.
我认识了一个男孩
I met a boy.
什么
What?
他叫克林特
His name's Clint.
我们
We--
我们要出去
We're going out,
约会
dating.
好吧
Okay.
他上的是普通高中
He goes to a regular high school.
他喜欢踢足球
He plays soccer.
爸爸是一名医生
His dad's a doctor.
我还没有告诉他我住在哪
I haven't told him where I live.
所以  他把我放到沙迪赛德的一个房子门口
So he... drops me outside a house in Shadyside and...
之后  我走回简之家
then I walk back to Jane's Place.
我有很多次都错过了宵禁  所以他们把我赶了出来
I've missed so many curfews, they kicked me out.
要知道  嗯
You know, uh--
最后  你总归得跟他实话实说
...eventually, you would have to tell him the truth.
跟他说我是一个妓女吗
That I was a hooker?
并不会像你想象的一样好
Doesn't exactly go over as well as you'd think.
好吧  蒂凡尼  有这样一个
Well, Tiffany-- there-- there's, uh--
有一个你的扣押令  所以
there's an attachment order out for you, so...
我知道  我需要进少管所
I know. I'm going to Juvie.
是的  我  我需要联系你的社工
Yeah. l-- I have to call your social worker.
有件事  今天晚上有一个舞会
Thing is... there's this dance tonight.
他邀请我参加春季舞会  我也特别想去
He invited me to the Spring Dance, and I really want to go.
我  我知道这可能听起来很愚蠢
Look, l-- I know it may sound stupid,
但是我从来没有参加过一次真正舞会
but I've never been to a real dance.
好了  这是一个感同身受的练习
Okay, this is an empathy exercise.
杰克将宣读事先准备好的声明
Jake will read from three prepared statements...
给他的搭档  伯顿  在这种情况下
to his partner-- Burton, in this case--
然后伯顿需要应答
and Burton will respond.
- 好的  - 可以吗
- Okay. - Okay?
就好像你在办公室  杰克有问题过来找你
As though you were in your office and Jake was coming to you with a problem.
- 哦  好的  -  明白了吗
- Oh, okay. - Okay?
- 好的  - 杰克
- Yeah. - Jake.
我不能再跟这个客户合作了
''l can't work with that client anymore.
他真的很没有礼貌
''He's rude and disrespectful.
他好像把我当成了清洁工  而不是律师
He treats me like I'm a cleaning woman, not an attorney.''
面对这种情况  你会要怎么说  伯顿
What would you say to that, Burton?
好吧  呃  客户是一个
Well, uh, a client is a--
一个混蛋客户  但是  呃
is a damn client, and, uh--
你知道的  我们不能感情用事
You know, we're not in the-- in the feeling business.
我们在处理法律业务  所以  如果他不能处理好
We're in the law business, so if he couldn't handle it,
那么我请他找能处理好的人来做
I would ask him to refer it to someone who can.
好的  伯顿
Okay, Burton.
这类问题的另一个解决方法
Another approach to this kind of problem
可以是成为你同事的一面镜子
would be to act as a mirror to your colleague.
怎么说呢
What does that mean?
比如  你可以说
Well, for instance, you could say,
杰克  听起来你是真的很不开心啊
''Jake, you sound like you're really upset.
能跟我说说发生了什么吗
Can you tell me what happened?''
你看  这样杰克就会觉得你是站在他这边的  而且他的心情对你来说是很重要的
You see, that way Jake knows that you're on his team and that his feelings matter.
- 好的  - 好的
- Okay. - All right.
杰克  读下一个
Jake, read another one.
我担心自己有没有在这周完成工作的能力
''I'm worried about my ability to finish my work this week.
我妈妈生病了  而且我的妻子也有些不舒服  待在家里
My mother is sick, and my wife is having some problems at home.''
那   我可能会说   我  听到这个消息我很难受
Well, I would certainly say, ''I'm-- I'm sorry to hear that.''
很好
Good.
那么接下来我又得说  你知道的
And I would say, you know, again,
如果你觉得你解决不了  那么
''if you feel like you can't handle it, though,
过来跟我说  我  我会找一个能做到的人来做
come tell me, and I'll-- I'll find someone who can.''
杰克  你有什么感受  告诉他
Jake. How's that make you feel? Tell him.
我也不知道  他平时就是这样的
I don't know. He's just being himself.
是的  但是你试着说一下你自己的感受
Right, but try to talk about your feelings,
当伯顿说  他会找别人来代替你完成工作
when Burton tells you he's going to refer your work to someone else.
我自己可以完成
''l would rather finish it myself.''
- 你想要一个成功的机会  - 当然
- You want a chance to succeed. - 'Course I do.
你更想要一些鼓励
You would like some encouragement.
你为什么笑
Why are you smiling?
好吧  我的意思是  这并不是  呃
Well, no, I mean, that's just not, um...
我  我  我的意思是  法林&法林律师事务所并不是完全像这样工作
l-- l-- I mean, Fallin & Fallin doesn't exactly work like that.
好吧  这是什么意思呢
Well, what does-- what does that mean?
没什么  我只是想说  那就是  就是
Nothing. I mean, that's just-- just the way-- it's the way--
杰克  就现在
Jake. Now's the time.
告诉他
Tell him.
各位  这就是我们来到这的原因
That's why we're here, everybody.
来吧
Come on.
好吧  我想说  在这种情况下
Okay. Well, I mean, in this situation,
我猜  嗯
I guess, that, um...
你可能会换掉我  然后让尼克来接手这个案子
you would probably take me off this deal and give it to Nick.
不  等一下
No. Wait. Wait a minute.
伯顿  杰克在试着跟你说他的感受
Burton, Jake is trying to tell you how he feels.
我知道  但是  我  我认为
I understand that, but, l-- I think, uh--
我想说  凭良心讲
I think I can honestly say
我一直尽量公平对待每一个人
that I have always tried to treat everybody the same.
是每一个人
Everybody.
你也许试了  但是并没有做到
You may try but you-- you don't.
你怎么会这么说
How can you say that?
得了吧  伯顿
Come on, Burton.
我想说  我们在这  困在这个地方
I mean, here we are, stuck in this place
做一些将心比心的练习  而
doing empathy exercises and...
尼克在洛杉矶
Nick is in L.A...
玩
having fun.
- 点心怎么样  - 还不错
- How 'bout that dim sum? - Good.
- 是啊  好东西  - 是的
- Yeah, good stuff. - Yep.
所有的这些  但是早餐有点奇怪
All those trays. Weird breakfast food, though.
鱼  和糯米
The fish, the sticky rice.
我很喜欢
I liked it.
尼克
Nick...
有个人  廖先生
There's this guy, Dr. Liao,
来自北京边上一个小镇子
from a small town outside of Beijing.
据说他有一些特异功能
He's supposed to have special abilities.
世界各地的人都去找他
People come to see him from all over the world.
我从网上肌萎缩侧索硬化交流群里一个女人那了解到他
I heard about him from some woman I met online, with ALS.
她七年前得的这个病  但是现在还能正常生活
She's had it for seven years. She still leads a pretty normal life.
她说她去找到他  他解救了她
She says she came to see him, and he helped her.
这就是我来洛杉矶的原因之一  为了找到他
That's one of the reasons I came to Los Angeles, to see him.
- 你预约了吗  - 是的  二十分钟之后
- Do you have an appointment? - Yeah. In twenty minutes.
- 那  我一会来找你  - 不  我  我想一起去
- So uh, I can just meet you later. - No, l-- I want to come.
真的
I do.
我真不敢相信  我刚吃完
I can't believe it. I just ate.
现在又饿了
I'm already hungry.
马斯特森先生吗
Mr. Masterson?
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
你感觉怎么样
What do you think?
快  下来  让我  看一看
Well, come down. Let me... take a look.
很漂亮
It looks good.
- 你这样觉得吗  - 是啊
- Think so? - Mm-hm.
如果  如果你想的话  我觉得我楼上可能有一些你会喜欢的东西
lf-- If you want, I think I might have some things upstairs that you might like.
真的吗
Really?
是啊  来吧
Yeah. Yeah. Come on.
所以
So...
我猜想我已经好了
I guess I'm healed now.
所以  卢·格里克  到梅奥诊所给自己检查了一下
So Lou Gehrig-- checks himself into the Mayo Clinic,
得到诊断之后  又回到了洋基体育馆
gets diagnosed, then goes back to Yankee Stadium,
在数千人面前做了演讲
makes a speech in front of thousands of people.
- 说他自己是多么的幸运  - 我看过那场演讲
- Says how lucky he is. - I've seen the speech.
两年之后  格里克死了
Two years later, Gehrig's dead.
37岁
Thirty-seven years old.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
呃  请带我们去回声公园
Uh, can you please take us to Echo Park?
滨海大道1023号
1023 Esplanade Avenue.
- 哦  好的  先生  - 谢谢
- Oh, yes sir. - Thank you.
去回声公园做什么
What's at Echo Park?
我  呃  我有没有跟你说过我的儿子
Did l, uh... ever tell you about my son?
我没有娶他的妈妈
I never married his mom.
我们处过一段  之后  呃
We had a brief fling and then, uh,
她怀孕了
she got pregnant.
大概是15年前的事了
That was almost 15 years ago.
是么
Whoa.
我上次见他时  他才7岁  现在应该上高中了
Last time I saw him, he was seven. He must be in high school now.
哦  我不知道该不该这么做
Oh... I don't know if I should do this.
不  阿尔文  你应该这样做
No, Alvin, you should.
我就
I just--
你应该这样做的
You should do it.
跟他说什么呢  说我刚好在这边吗
Just tell him what? l-- I was in the neighborhood?
就  就直接告诉他  你想见他
Just-- just tell him that you want to see him.
- 是么  - 我的意思是  你不需要说为什么的
- Yeah. - I mean, you don't have to say why.
是啊
Yeah.
詹妮弗
Jennifer.
这么快
That was fast.
他不想见我
Didn't want to see me.
他都不肯从房间出来
Wouldn't come out of his room.
说他已经有爸爸了
Said he already has a dad.
我们回酒店吧
Let's go back to the hotel.
我有点累了
I'm kind of tired.
蒂凡尼  他到了
Tiffany. He's here.
哇  你真漂亮
Wow. You look great.
- 你真的很漂亮  - 谢谢
- You look really great. - Thank you.
好吧  那  呃  好好玩
Okay, well, uh, have fun.
但是12点之前要回家
But you be home by midnight,
否则的话  你知道的  我就得报警了
or you know I'm going to have to call the police.
我知道
I know.
- 谢谢  - 好啦
- Thank you. - Okay.
- 拜  - 拜
- Bye. - Bye.
- 阿尔文  我回来了  - 我在这
- Alvin. I'm back. - I'm in here.
你没跟我说游泳池是热的
You didn't tell me the pool was heated.
我感觉我在走廊看到了吉娜·戴维斯
You know, I think I saw Geena·Davis in the hallway.
你在做什么  在收拾行李吗
What're you doing? You packing?
- 十点有一趟航班  - 什么  单身聚会结束了吗
- There's a 10:00flight. - What, the party's over?
是啊
Yeah.
呃  那这个我该怎么处理呢
Ah, what am I going to do with these?
湖人的票
Laker tickets?
场边  今晚的
Courtside. Tonight.
一张票1900美金
You paid $1,900 a ticket?
- 花了这些钱吗  - 哦  尼克
- Is that what they cost? - Oh, Nick.
退了吧
Return them.
阿尔文  来吧  是湖人的  场边哦
Alvin, come on. It's the Lakers-- courtside.
跟杰克聊会天  然后去吃些寿司
Have a chat with Jack. Go and get some Sushi afterwards.
- 不了  谢谢  - 你确定
- Thanks, no. - Are you sure?
我只想回家
I just want to go home.
好吧  好的 算了吧  去他的湖人
All right. Okay. Fine. Screw the Lakers.
那  我们  我们出去走走
We'll, uh-- we'll go for a walk.
我们可以就聊聊  在逛一逛  然后吃点东西
We can just talk about this and hang out, get something to eat.
不要
No.
阿尔文  你不能把我拽来这里  在把我丢在这不管
Alvin, you can't drag me across the country and then just drop me.
你知道匹兹堡现在有多冷么
You know how cold it is in Pittsburgh now?
现在是31度  31度
It's 31 degrees, right now, 31 degrees.
好吧  好吧
Okay, fine.
我们去吃晚饭  你来选地方
We'll get some dinner. You pick the place.
- 好吧  - 我正要出去走走
- Good. - I'm just going to go for a walk.
你自己吗
On your own?
是的  如果你不介意的话
Yeah, if you don't mind.
当然不介意
I don't mind.
伯顿  关于今天
Burton, about today...
嗯
Yeah.
我很抱歉  我就是
I'm sorry, I just--
我道歉
I apologize.
希望我说的话没有太过分
And I hope what I said wasn't out of line.
那个家伙想让我们说  所以
Well, that guy wanted us to talk, so...
你知道  说起来
You know, that said...
我并不觉得这个竞技场是公平的
I don't feel that the playing field is level.
我的意思是  我为客户着想
I mean, I land clients.
我花了比别人更多的时间
I bill more hours than anyone else.
无论什么时候  我都尽量帮忙
l-- I help out whenever needed,
让我做什么  我就做什么
and I do whatever I'm asked to do,
但是  但是  尼克依然是
and-- and still Nick is...
我的上级
senior to me.
你在考虑更换管理层
You're considering a management change.
我  我知道的
l-- I know that and, uh...
我也知道  尼克肯定是
I know that Nick is clearly the--
继承人
the heir apparent.
还不一定  杰克
Not necessarily, Jake.
好吧  如果  如果真的是这样
Well, if-- if-- if that's true...
你应该考虑考虑我
you should consider me.
嘿  你回来了
Hey. You're back early.
怎么样
How was it?
他们把健身房弄的像夏威夷一样
They made the gym look like it was Hawaiian.
有沙子和火把
Sand and torches.
我是说  不是真的火把
I mean, they weren't real torches.
还有音乐
And the music.
真不错
That's cool.
普通高中的女孩看起来很不同
Girls at regular high school are so different.
发生什么了吗
Did something happen?
你什么时候生宝宝啊
When's your baby coming?
还有几个月
ln a few months.
男孩还是女孩呢
Boy or a girl?
告诉我怎么了  蒂凡尼
Tell me what's going on, Tiffany.
- 我全跟克林特说了  - 哦
- I told Clint the truth. - Oh.
说了我怎么会沦落到简之家
About how I ended up in Jane's Place.
还有少管所的事儿
About Juvie.
所有的事情
Everything.
好吧
Okay.
一会之后  他什么都没跟我说
He kind of stopped talking to me after a while.
只和他的朋友们喝酒
Drank with his friends.
叫我鸡
Called me a whore.
所以我就走了
So I left.
走回家
Walked home.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
所以  是个男孩还是女孩呢
So... are you having a boy or a girl?
阿尔文
Alvin.
我都想你了
I missed you.
肌萎缩性脊髓侧索硬化症
Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis.
是个希腊词组
It's a Greek phrase.
A的意思是负的
''A'' meaning negative.
Myo的意思是肌肉
''Myo'' meaning muscles.
Trophic的意思是营养
''Trophic'' meaning nourishment.
你知道  我正试着不去想它
I'm trying to get my mind around it, you know?
运动神经元退化
Motor neurons degenerate...
直到大脑不能给肌肉传递冲动
until the brain can't send impulses to the muscles.
当肌肉无法接受这些信息  就会萎缩
When the muscles can't receive messages, they atrophy.
之后我的大脑
And my brain--
我的大脑还是那样
my brain stays the same.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
所以  尼克
So Nick...
我正在想
I was thinking...
我可以向西游到多远
of seeing how far west I could swim.
我不知道我能不能做到
I don't know if I have it in me.
那维多利亚怎么办
What about Victoria?
哦  她会她会离开的
Oh... she's going to walk away.
至少她应该
At least she should.
我的意思是  我在想什么
I mean, what was I thinking?
我的意思是
I mean...
我就要死了
I am going to die.
我要死了  尼克
I am going to die, Nick.
你知道的
You know that.
你不用坐在这的
You don't have to sit here.
我知道  我明白的
I know. I know.
阿尔文  我都好了
Alvin, I'm ready.
呃  我正要下楼到打听等着
Uh... I'm just going to head down to the lobby and wait.
- 我要定一辆出租车吗  - 已经有一辆豪华轿车了
- Shall I call a cab? - Already got us a limo.
- 楼下见  - 好的
- I'll see you down there. - All right.
等一下
One second.
我来了  尼克
I'm coming, Nick.
抵达航班的旅客
Arriving passengers on flight--
阿尔文  这个周末  真的是  呃  太棒了
Well, Alvin, the weekend was, uh... fantastic.
是啊
Yeah.
实在是
It was.
太感谢你了  呃  关于我的儿子
And thank you, uh... with my son.
谢谢你的安排
Thanks for setting that up.
哦  谢谢
Oh, thank you.
捎你一段吗
Need a ride?
- 不  有人来接我  - 就知道会这样
- No, I've got it. - I'm sure you do.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
玩的开心吗
Did you have fun?
我们很开心
We did.
没惹麻烦吧
Did you stay out of trouble?
当然
Yes.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
等一下
Hang on.
嘿  你回来了
Hey. You're back.
抱歉  我就是来看看你
Sorry to just drop in on you.
没事
That's okay.
我  只是  呃  好吧  我很想看看你
I just, uh-- Well, I really wanted to see you.
进来吧
Come in.
我不想你离开
I don't want you to go.
露露  这样很好  但是  呃
Well, that's kind, Lulu, but, uh--
阿尔文  这是你的事务所
Alvin, this is your clinic.
我想说  我在这  但是  我只是
I mean, I'm here, but, I'm just--
- 这是你的事务所  - 谢谢
- This is your clinic. - Thank you.
所以你会留下来吗
So you'll stay?
你希望我留下来吗
You want me to stay?
- 当然  - 为什么  因为我生病了吗
- Yes. - Why? Because I'm sick?
因为  因为你是不可或缺的
Because... you're indispensable...
不论你信不信
believe it or not.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道的  我  呃
You know, l, uh--
我和你的客户度过了愉快的一个周末
I had an interesting weekend with one of your clients.
- 是么  - 蒂凡尼·斯科维奇
- Really? - Tiffany·Skovich?
- 阿尔文  - 最近怎么样  伯尼
- Alvin. - How are you, Bernie?
挺好的
I'm fine.
有什么我能帮你的吗
What can I do for you?
我就是  呃  想为我之前说的话道歉
I just, uh, want to apologize for saying what I said.
我当时说把它推到你的屁股里什么的很过分
I was way out of line telling you to shove it up your ass like that.
但是我来这的主要原因是我的客户  蒂凡尼·斯科维奇
But the main reason I'm here is my client Tiffany·Skovich.
我需要让她重新回到简之家
I need to get her back into Jane's Place.
呃  她因为反复违反宵禁要求被开除了
Uh, she was expelled for repeated curfew violations.
事实上  她爱上了一个塞威克利预科学校的男孩
Well, she fell in love with a boy from Sewickley Prep.
不想他把她送到
Didn't want him to drop her off
一个未成年妓女的陪护所  你明白吗
at a shelter for teenage hookers, you know?
- 我能理解  但是  - 她值得再给一次机会
- I understand but, uh-- - She deserves another chance.
- 已经给了她四次机会了  - 那就再给她第五次吧
- She's already had four. - Then give her five.
不行  很抱歉
No. Sorry.
我们已经是很多年的朋友了  伯尼
We've been friends a long time, Bernie.
是的
Right.
希望你能理解
Want you to know...
我得了肌萎缩侧索硬化症
I have ALS.
我的天哪  阿尔文  真的是太遗憾了
My, God, Alvin. I'm so sorry.
所以  也会不要求你帮更多的忙了
So... won't be asking you for many more favors,
反正也不会太久了
not for much longer anyway.
你在情感勒索我
You're manipulating me.
是啊
I am.
请进
Come in.
你要找我吗
You wanted to see me?
是啊  嘿  快请进
Yeah, hey. Come on in.
请坐
Sit down.
最近怎么样
How you doing?
很好
Good.
听着  呃
Listen, uh...
你说的关于尼古拉斯的事情
what you said about Nicholas...
我觉得你说的有道理
I think you're right.
很多时候  我更偏爱他
There are times when I favor him...
但是我就是希望你能明白  呃
and I just wanted you to know that, uh...
我会时刻记住的
I'm going to keep that in mind.
谢谢
Thank you.
发型不错
Your hair looks great.
- 嗨  尼克  - 嘿  杰克
- Hi, Nick. - Hey, Jake.
那  呃  爸爸  呃  关于周末
So uh, Dad, uh, about the weekend--
好吧  你说过是私事的
Well, I thought you said it was personal.
我记得你说过的
I'll take you at your word.
是的
Right.
但是能解释为什么我一定要走
Well, I can explain why I had to go.
我记得你之前说过的  尼古拉斯
I'll take you at your word, Nicholas.
好吧
Right.
她不肯放过我
She won't let me off the hook.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我告诉维多利亚了  但她仍然想跟我结婚
I told Victoria. She still wants to get married.
真是好消息
Well, that's great news.
所以  不管你想不想  这个伴郎你是做定了
So, like it or not, you're stuck being my Best Man.
你知道的
You know...
我一直在想  那个治愈者
I've been thinking... about that healer.
是的
Right.
谁又知道呢
Well, who knows?
- 可能就有效果了  - 很可能
- Maybe it worked. - Maybe.
- 如果没有效果  - 但是  可能会有效果
- If it didn't... - Well, maybe it did work.
卢·格里克的最后一季  1939
Lou Gehrig's final season-- 1939.
他遇到些问题  没人知道是什么问题
Something was wrong with him, didn't know what it was.
他仍然打了八场  还有四个安打
He still played in eight games. Still got four hits.
- 四个吗  - 之前一年
- Four? - Year before that...
他死前三年
three years before he died...
格里克打了.295
Gehrig batted .295,
打了29个本垒打
hit 29 home runs.
- 29  - 哇哦
- 29. -Wow.
想想这个  尼克
Think about it, Nick.
实在是厉害
That's a lot of hitting.
失陪
Excuse me.
最后一次了  你知道的
This is it. You know that.
决不允许再错过宵禁
No more missing curfews.
好的
Right.
我说真的  我
I mean it. l--
以后再遇到这种情况我也帮不了你了
I can't keep getting you out of these situations.
还有  蒂凡尼  你得把我的钥匙还给我了
And, Tiffany, you're going to have to give me my key back.
你是个好孩子  蒂凡尼
You're a great kid, Tiffany.
尽量乖一点
Try to stay put.
呃  你们先到我办公室等一下吧  我马上就到
Uh... you can step into my office. I'll be right in.
你给了她钥匙吗
You gave her your key?
我可没有
I did no such thing.
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177